ABOUT ME

My Name is Chad.

I'm a 28 year-old Senior Front-end Engineer and Front-end Team Lead, living and working in Denver. I love to build challenging, visually exciting, and unique applications on the web.

One of my favorite things about development is the massive toolbox of languages, libraries, and methodologies that you can pull from. I am not one of those people who thinks if you want to be good at design, you have to be bad at logic, or vise-versa. I like to pride myself on being excellent at all aspects of web development.

I have been working in the space for about 6 years now, starting from Junior Dev and moving up to Team Lead in my current position.

BlueModus

2017 - Present

Hired as a UX/UI Developer, within three years I was promoted to Senior UX/UI Developer and finally to UX/UI Development Lead. During this time, I was responsible for spearheading the company into the transition from ¡Query to Vanilla JS. I also implemented the practice of using Vue.JS for all large SPA builds, and API Components.

As Team Lead, it is my responsibility to train and code review my teammates, and other coworkers in the company, on the latest best practices in Front-end development.

Co-created, and actively maintain our custom front-end build tool (BlueTasks) written in node, to replace Gulp.JS.

EXPERIENCE

2016 - 2017

Bridgeline Digital

Hired as a Junior Front-end Developer. I was named employee of the month via a peer vote, during my second month with the company, for my work on implementing a Front-end build tool to automate many previously manual processes.

Additionally, I was responsible for creating and maintaining several custom ¡Query plugins to simplify common design patterns and requirements.

Wesco Fabrics

2013 - 2016

Hired as administrative assistant, but transitioned to Catalog Designer, and Web Developer. Completely redesigned and developed a new ecommerce website with integration into their inventory control system.

SKILLS

HTML5

CSS3+

JavaScript ES6+

Vue.IS

Node.JS

Webpack • Rollup • Browserify

Gulp.JS

jQuery

Sketch

Photoshop • Illustrator

Git • GitHub • Bitbucket

IIRA • Basecamp • Confluence

Kentico • Sitecore

I also have experience with: React./S Angular.JS WordPress

RECENT PROJECTS

American Campus Communities 25th Anniversary

https://www.americancampus.com/timeline [Assisted in Design | Full FE Build]

Arthritis Foundation

https://www.arthritis.org/

[Full FE Build | Vanilla.]S (main site) | Vue.]S (Search, Health Resources, Find a Doctor)]

American Society for Biochemistry and Molecular Biology

https://www.asbmb.org/ [Lead FE | Vanilla.JS]

RILA Retail Compliance Center Matrix Application

https://www.rila.org/retail-compliance-center/hazardous-waste-generator-reporting [Filterable Matrix Table – scroll down] [Full FE Build | Design | Vue.|S] [Not Visible: Includes an interactive admin-only state for adding, deleting, and sorting rows of data.1

United Heritage Credit Union

https://uhcu.org [Full FE Build | Vanilla.JS | Vue.JS]

EDUCATION

Udemy Courses (Various) Ongoing

Team Treehouse Front-end Track

University of Colorado Denver BA History 2016